# **KUDAKWASHE GUDYANGA**

# Frontend Developer | Mentor | Team Leader

📞 +263780121672 – @ kudakwashegudyanga41@gmail.com.com 🛮 🔗 linkedin.com/Kudakwashe Gudyanga Hre Zimbabwe

#### **STRENGTHS**



## Coding Expert

Proficient in HTML, CSS, JS

@ github.com/kudakwashe gudyanga



#### Problem Solver

Innovative approach to challenges



## Team Player

Excellent collaboration skills

#### **SKILLS**

**HTML** 

CSS

**JavaScript** 

Responsive Design

Next.is

React

**TypeScript** 

GIT

Node.js

SQL

MongoDB

PHP

Performance Optimization

#### INDUSTRY EXPERTISE

#### Front-end develoment

# **Backend Development**



### LANGUAGES

**English** Native •

Shona Native ••••

Spanish Beginner • • • •

#### SUMMARY

Passionate Frontend Developer with a knack for creating intuitive and highperforming web applications.

I excel at motivating, mentoring & developing teams of less experienced developers. Ready to bring coding expertise and innovative problem-solving skills to world of tech and solve the challenges of computer literacy

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Frontend Developer

#### Declanfreelance.org

🗰 2021 - Present Remote

Worked on various web development projects

- Contributed to the development of 15+ websites
- Reduced page load time on 10 client websites by 30% through a number of optimization techniques. Became the company expert on load time, web vitals.
- Implemented responsive design for improved mobile experience in client project that won an UX awards by the Lion Foundation.

## **Junior Frontend Developer**

YouPro Contact

i 10/2024 - Ongoing

Harare cbd

Assisted in the development of web applications

- · Worked on 22 web development projects
- Improved website accessibility following WCAG guidelines Received 'Rising Star' award for outstanding performance

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Front end development

Uncommon.org

**=** 01/2024 - Ongoing

Harare Zimbabwe

## High school

Mufakose high 2

**=** 2020

Location